import type { Question } from './questionTypes'

const station4Questions: Question[] = [
  {
    question: 'What is the molten rock erupted from a volcano or fissure called?',
    answers: ['Magma', 'Lava', 'Tephra'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the depression, usually located at the summit or flank of a volcano, directly above the vent from which volcanic material (lava, ash, gas) is erupted called?',
    answers: ['Crater', 'Mantle', 'Crust'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
  {
    question: 'What are destructive, fast-flowing volcanic mudflows or debris flows made of water, ash, rock, and other volcanic debris called?',
    answers: ['Lahar', 'Pyroclastic flow', 'Geyser'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the hot, fluid material inside or below earth’s crust called?',
    answers: ['Magma', 'Mantle', 'Crust'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is a hot spring in which water intermittently boils, sending a tall column of water and steam into the air called?',
    answers: ['Geyser', 'Tephra', 'Crater'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the string of volcanoes and sites of seismic activity around the edges of the Pacific Ocean where roughly 90% of all earthquakes and 75% of all active volcanoes on Earth are found known as?',
    answers: ['Ring of Fire', 'Crust', 'Mantle'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the thin, rocky, outermost layer of Earth, divided into thicker continental and thinner oceanic layers called?',
    answers: ['Crust', 'Mantle', 'Pyroclastic flow'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the dense, destructive mass of very hot ash, lava fragments, and gases ejected explosively from a volcano and typically flowing downslope at great speed called?',
    answers: ['Pyroclastic flow', 'Lahar', 'Tephra'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the thick, hot, dense layer of molten rock beneath the Earth’s surface often referred to in geology as a major interior layer?',
    answers: ['Mantle', 'Crust', 'Magma'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the general term for any fragmented volcanic material (rock, glass, minerals) ejected into the air during an eruption?',
    answers: ['Tephra', 'Pyroclastic flow', 'Lahar'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    category: 'Volcanoes',
  },
]

export default station4Questions
